Every good solution has a pain. Tell me
what the problem is that we're trying to
solve here at Tesla, but also AI and D
and things like that is trying to solve.
>> If you're using agents to develop, then
you've probably seen that agents are
powerful, but they're also unreliable.
You would ask them for something that go
off and they rush to start coding the
first solution that comes to mind. And
often times that would be the wrong
thing. For some people, they just can't
get into agentic development because of
this blocker. And so we think we can
address many of these problems through
specs and specri development. That's
what both of our products are trying to
solve.
[Music]
>> What are the two products that we're
releasing?
>> Uh so two products, both very exciting.
Um the first one is the Tesla framework
and that is really a specdriven
development framework that connects to
your agent via MCP. So we support all
the agents that support it. uh and
guides it to uh capture its intent in
specs before it builds. Right? So you
come along and you give it an
instruction whatever build me a uh to-do
app or whatever it is. Uh and before it
jumps into code, it first creates a spec
thanks to using Tesla's tools and thanks
to Tesla's guidance to say what is it
that it wants to build in a quick and
easy to understand format and then it
goes off to build it. And have you had a
case where you ran along or you gave an
instruction and the agent rushed and
they ended up building the wrong thing?
>> It's it's not just daily, maybe hourly
when I when I when I use agents. Um, and
it's it's I guess a twofold thing. One
where I either give it an instruction
and it hasn't quite understood exactly
what I meant. And it's because I love to
short prompt because I get, you know,
value and speed out of short prompting.
Uh the other of course is where I you
know I ask it for a small a small change
in a larger app and it actually then
goes ahead and starts changing other
pieces
>> expands it of the
>> oh gosh it's frustrating. So, so that's
the sort of the first goal is separate
intent from implementation and capture
what it means to build in a spec and
then once you are comfortable with you
know the the intent and with what has
been built and you're happy with it uh
then Tesla offers you an easy way to now
generate tests uh with sort of a single
command uh and this is done because the
spec is actually designed up front to be
built with a lot of test cases in mind
that serve as examples when you
initially generate Right? But then those
uh are are sort of the key definitions
to go off and create tests. And the
agent needs to work a little bit harder
to be able to generate those tests.
Needs to set up a test environment,
sometimes iterate, uh but it does it
quite autonomously. And once it works,
those serve as regression tests. And so
now you know that it would not do as you
mentioned before, you know, you you make
a change, then goes off and it breaks
something else.
>> So the second product which I'm very
excited about is the Tesla spec
registry. Going back a little bit to the
pain point, I think what you see with
agents is uh sometimes they don't know
something and they don't know they don't
know. Uh or you know, as I said,
>> the story of my life. I'm basically an
agent.
>> They're kind of uh they're kind of
overconfident. You know, I'm not I'm
going to let that slide.
>> I feel seen now.
>> So, the most evident version of that is
when they use an API, a third party API
or or an open source library API. Uh if
you're using something that is like
straight up in the mainstream and they
know they're amazing at it. If you're
using something that's a little bit off
or using a slightly older version of a
popular library or even more if you're
using a new version that didn't exist
yet when those models were trained uh
typically what the agents would do is
they would just make it up as they go
and they would use you know false APIs
or flawed one and sometimes they would
just really get stuck in that mode and
they would just sort of waste time and
money trying to get there and never get
out of it and sometimes they would
eventually figure it out but it was you
know timeconuming costly And they often
times are left with a slightly messy
implementation. And have you experienced
things like that?
>> So much. So much. And it's particularly
because you know AI is great at when it
looks at its when it you know trains on
on a huge amount of of open source
libraries with tons of different
versions on there. When things and I'm
talking about the Java world here, but
when things progress over years and
years and years and years, there are so
many API changes from different
libraries whereby the most popular is
really the one it's going to be trained
on. And I'm not always using the most
popular because I sometimes run on an
old stack or I'm sometimes bleeding edge
with some of the things I'm using. And
it's not just as much a hallucination as
it is a I'm assuming this is the version
you're running on without actually using
the correct context to build against uh
when generating my app. Huge problem
>> precisely. And so we this is really a
kind of a context problem, right? They
don't have the right information at the
right time. Sometimes because they
literally do not have the info like a
brand new library version. sometimes
because sort of a a less statistically
significant bit of information. Uh and
sometimes it's indeed information that
there's no way for them to have like
your team's specific best practices or
context. Um and so what we believe and
enable with the spec registry is to make
that knowledge a part of your project.
Um so we introduced a new dependency
system that the spec registry enables
that is a dependency system for
knowledge for specs. uh you would have a
a new manifest file in your project that
references certain spec packs, packages
of specs with the right information to
be able to work on this codebase. More
specifically for open source, we have
pre-populated uh the registry with over
10,000 usage specs which are uh pre like
we generated them by analyzing the code
of specific versions of libraries uh and
additional information about those
libraries of you know usage online that
is all version aware and we package them
up in these easy to consume kind of
nuggets of knowledge for the agent. So
these are markdown files with the right
sections. they are split up into
multiple files so the agent can load the
right thing at the right time and so
let's say you're using some library at
you know version old then the agent will
uh you you will add that you would use
Tesla registry search to find uh the
usage spec you will it will be added to
your manifest file and those usage specs
will be downloaded to your uh your
project just like node modules or other
dependencies uh and then using tesla
tools and even natively the agent can
then find them and use the information
correctly and you know that this
information is there. It is uh uh
correct for your specific project. It is
uh um kind of always available to all
the agents. You're not dependent on them
realizing they need to go seek it out or
misunderstanding it. Uh and as your
software stack changes or as your
practices change, so does the
information that you make available to
the agents. So both products together
are to us a part of what is specdriven
development. If you're keen to try them
out, just check out del.io and start
playing with the tools.